A Guide to the Secretary of Natural Resources, Correspondence and Subject Files, 1998-2001
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Correspondence and subject files, 1998-2001
Library of Virginia
38944
16 cubic feet
Virginia Secretary of Natural Resources
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Office of the Secretary of Natural Resources on January 11, 2002.
Historical Information
Governor Linwood Holton's top priority for the 1972 session of the General Assembly was a proposal for a Governor's Cabinet, reorganizing state agencies into six major departments-each headed by a secretary appointed by the governor. Commerce and Resources was one of these six departments. The Office of Secretary of Commerce and Resources was created on April 8, 1972, by an act passed by the General Assembly. In 1984, the name of the office was changed to the Secretary of Natural Resources. The Secretary of Natural Resources is a member of the Governor's Cabinet, and is appointed by the governor, subject to confirmation by the General Assembly. The Secretary is responsible to the governor for the Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, Dept. of Historic Resources, Marine Resources Commission, Dept. of Game and Inland Fishers, Chippokes Plantation Farm Foundation, Chesapeake Bay Local Assistance Dept., Virginia Museum of Natural History, and the Dept. of Environmental Quality. The Secretary of Natural Resources also monitors and reports on water and resources of the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries, as well as the "Friend of the Bay Award" program. The Secretary also appoints members to the Boating Advisory Committee.
Scope and Content Information
This collection is comprised of the Secretary of Natural Resources, John Paul Woodley, Jr.'s, correspondence and subject files, 1998-2001, under Governor James S. Gilmore. The subject files that are included are: Interstate Waste, Horseshoe Crabs, the King William Reservoir and Mattaponi Indians, Wetlands and the Tulloch Rule, Beavers at Tysons Corner, and Proposed Power Plants. They contain letters and e-mail from constituents along with routing slips, people summaries and responses. The agency correspondence includes letters to the governor from Ronald P. Hamm, John Paul Woodley, Dennis H. Tracy, David G. Brickley, and Alex Wise.
Organization
The collection is arranged into two (2) series: Constituent Correspondence, 1998-2001 and Agency Correspondence, 1998-2001. Each series is described in the box and folder listing.
Contents List
- Series I: Constituent correspondence, 1998-2001
  Arranged numerically by Constituent ID number.
  - General correspondence, ID no. 172 through 32,409, 1998 Feb 3 through 1998 September 8 (Box 1)
  - General correspondence, ID no. 32,427 through 65,419, 1998 September 9 through 1999 April 2 (Box 2)
  - General correspondence, ID no. 65,481 through 93,147, 1999 April 2 through 1999 November 8 (Box 3)
  - General correspondence, ID no. 93,150 through 115,749, 1999 November 8 through 2000 April 17 (Box 4)
  - General correspondence, ID no. 115,750 through 2014092, 2000 April 17 through 2000 August 23 (Box 4a)
  - Interstate Waste, ID no. 849 through 32,991, 1998 February 9 through 1998 Sept 16 (Box 5)
  - Interstate Waste, ID no. 33,000 through 51,580, 1998 Sept 17 through 1999 January 8 (Box 6)
  - Interstate Waste and DEQ Agency Head Appointment, ID no. 13,661 through 38,621; Horseshoe Crabs, ID no. 53,335 through 98,343, 1998 March 18 through 1999 December 16 (Box 7)
  - King William Reservoir and Mattaponi Indians, ID no. 57,353 through 95,193, 1999 February 24 through 1999 November 22 (Box 8)
  - Wetlands and the Tulloch Rule, ID no. 60,535 through 74,649, 1999 March 11 through 1999 June 21 (Box 9)
  - Wetlands and the Tulloch Rule, ID no. 74,651 through 98,372, 1999 June 21 through 1999 December 16 (Box 10)
  - General correspondence, ID no. 2006815 through 2039633; Beavers at Tysons Corner, ID no. 2028280 through 2035976; Interstate Waste, ID no. 2026998 through 2027643; Proposed power plants, ID no. 2026566 through 2037752, 2000 July 3 through 2000 December 31 (Box 11)
  - General correspondence, ID no. 2037265 through 2081907, 2001 January 4 through 2001 September 20 (Box 12)
  - General correspondence, ID no. 2081908 through 2088562, 2001 September 20 through 2001 Dec 13 (Box 13)
- Series II: Agency correspondence, 1998-2001
  Arranged by department.
  - Chesapeake Bay Local Assistance Department (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Department of Conservation and Recreation (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Land Conservation Fund (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Department of Environmental Quality, Administrative and Misc. Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Department of Environmental Quality, Air Division (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Department of Environmental Quality, Waste Division (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Department of Environmental Quality, Water Division (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Department of Game and Inland Fisheries (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Department of Historic Resources (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Museum of Natural History (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Marine Resources Commission (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Chesapeake Bay Programs (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Office of Secretary of Natural Resources (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence to Governor and from Governor's staff (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Legislative: correspondence to members of the General Assembly concerning legislation (Box 15, Folder 8)